Carlos Canas

Community Support Lead at Wattpad

carloscanas87@gmail.com

Summary

I am a results-oriented and passionate Community Management Professional. I am fascinated by disruptive technology and how its innovations are impacting the world we live in. By day I have the pleasure of providing support to the amazing Wattpad Community. By night I am a continuous learner, whether it's online, in the classroom or with others, I enjoy improving my knowledge of all things Community. I have professional experience in project management, customer/technical support, community management, and content curation in both English and Spanish. Technical Skills: Google Analytics, Zendesk, Uservoice, Omnigraffle, SQL, HTML, CSS, Javascript

Experience

Community Support Lead at Wattpad

January 2014 - Present (1 year 8 months)

My role is to lead Wattpad's support team and execute on a global support strategy for over 60 million users. With only eight people on the team we punch above our weight class by providing help to users in volumes that would scare most support teams. All while maintaining a low first response time and a high customer satisfaction rating.

Interim Spanish Community Manager at Wattpad

February 2014 - March 2015 (1 year 2 months)

During this time I temporarily stepped in to help manage the growing Spanish Community on Wattpad. Responsibilities included but were not limited to: - Curating high quality content. - Establishing relations with high profile users. - Recruiting and training volunteer team of organizers and moderators. - Product translations. - Representing the Spanish Community at Wattpad HO.

Community Support Specialist at Wattpad

February 2013 - December 2013 (11 months)

- Responsible for providing community and technical support to over 25 million Wattpad Users in both English and Spanish. - Responsible for the front-end development of Wattpad's support site. - Worked with Developers and other Team Members to develop and implemented stronger work flows for handling increasing support demand. - Responsible for the communication of key messages to User Community.

Website Content Specialist at CN

November 2012 - February 2013 (4 months)

- Responsible for using Sitecore Content Management System to create and implement content for new Corporate Website. - Performed quality assurance on a newly implemented CMS. - Tested and fixed HTML and CSS errors in various webpages. - Coordinated with I.T and Marketing Departments to help Website meet organizational standards.

Content Evaluator at Mind Your Mind

November 2011 - October 2012 (1 year)

Content and program evaluation contributor for Mind Your Mind, a Canada-wide online and in-person program that creates resources to eliminate stigma and promote conversations about mental health among youth and professionals who serve them.

Skills & Expertise

CSS

Community Management

Social Networking

Teamwork

Customer Service

Team Leadership

Public Speaking

Problem Solving

Microsoft Office

HTML 5

Photoshop

Strategic Planning

Database Administration

JavaScript

Spanish

Research

Social Media

Technical Support

Human Resources

Front-end Development

Zendesk

Forum Management

Eclipse

Github

Windows

Mac OS X

Education

Ryerson University

Certificate, Computer Programming Applications, 2013 - 2014

The University of Western Ontario

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), Politics/Economics, 2007 - 2011

Activities and Societies: Student Council President (10-11), Student Council Vice President of Operations (09-10), Orientation Leader (07-09)

John Paul II Catholic Secondary

H.S Diploma, 2002 - 2006

Languages

English

Spanish

Carlos Canas

Community Support Lead at Wattpad

carloscanas87@gmail.com



Contact Carlos on LinkedIn